this is going to be a fun problem we
have a shed that has a 6 m x 6 M area
right here and then a side room that's a
3 MX 3 m then tied to this corner of a
shed is a leash for a goat this leash is
7 m long here's the goat right here and
as we all know Andy is the goat if we
wanted to analyze the amount of grass
that the goat could eat usually
something like this where it forms a
circle around where the leash is pinned
is the center of the circle and then it
goes out with a radius that's as long as
the leash normally a goat would be able
to eat all of this grass you go inside
the circle because the leash isn't stiff
but we do have these buildings in the
way so we got to calculate how much
grass can the goat eat with these
buildings that are in the way so first
off we can bring the goat over here and
we can see that he can eat all of this
very important detail here is what angle
is this this is
225° how do we know that we know the
half of the circle would be 180° and
then since this is three and we know
this whole side is six that means each
of these are equal to three and so we
have a 3X3 triangle which means this has
to be 45° so 180 + 45 is 225° so let's
calculate the area of this piece right
here well normally a circle would beunk
R 2 this is 225° out of the total 360°
of the circle and 225 over 360
simplifies to 5 over8 so this is 58 of
an entire circle with radius 7 so we can
change this R into a seven next we have
this red piece right here and it looks
like this here so what is the radius of
this well the whole length of the leash
is seven so we're using up six of it to
get to this side of the shed that means
that from here we have one more meter
that can pivot around and make a quarter
of a circle so this has a radius of 1 M
and then we can see that this makes a
90° angle once again we have the area of
a circle is PK R squ this is 1/4 of an
entire circle so we'll call it 1/4 PK R
squar and then we can plug in one for R
plug this into a calculator and get
approximately 785 next thing we have
this orange triangle and you can see
that the goat would be able to eat
everything inside of this orange
triangle so let's Analyze This each of
these two sides is three and to get this
hypotenuse here since since it's a
454590 triangle we know that that is 3 <
tk2 m and if you want to see the work
behind it here it is right here using
Pythagorean theorem you can pause it and
look at this if you want the area of a
triangle is 1/2 base time height this
triangle is upside down but this base is
going to be three and this height is
going to be three and this all
simplifies to give us 4.5 next let's do
this up here let's move the goat out of
the way and then we're looking at this
piece right here now doesn't follow all
the way we can zoom in and look at it it
goes kind of like this so it's going to
have a different radius than the circle
irle so that's why it's not following
the whole circle it's kind of like what
was going on over here with the red one
because you have a pivot point that
creates a new Mini Circle so let's look
at this pie slice right here well the
easy part is seeing that that's going to
be 45° it's the same thing as this 45
right here so we know this is going to
be 45° the trickier part is finding the
radius so we're going to call the radius
R the goat were up here we're going to
be using up a portion of the leash I'm
going to show that leash right here and
we showed earlier that that length is 3
< tk2 so we know that as far as this
goat can reach is 7 that means that 3 <
tk2 + r has to be equal to 7 that's as
far as the leash will reach we have to
subtract 3 < tk2 from both sides to find
out r r is equal to 7 - 3 < tk2 that's
approximately 2757 if we clean all this
stuff up let's find the area of this
yellow piece p r squ is the area of a
circle but we're dealing with 45° out of
360 that's going to be 1/8 of an entire
circle and then we can substitute 2757
in for the r plug this into a calculator
we get approximately
2986 so now we have the areas this red
green orange and yellow shape make up
everything that this goat can possibly
eat if we add up these four areas we'll
know how much the goat can eat and
that's the answer to the question how
exciting